JORDAN "JJ" CARDENAS

📞 425-922-3350 🛘 💌 jjcardenas16@hotmail.com 🛅 linkedin.com/in/jordanjcardenas 📅 www.jjcardenas.com



SUMMARY

Recent graduate of an intensive full stack development program backed by five years as a marketing professional in the technology industry. Dedicated, personable, fast learner seeking an entry-level front-end developer role where I can combine my marketing knowledge with my new-found technical skills to help reach millions by building the next great experience.

TECHNOLOGIES

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- **j**Query

- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Node.is
- Java

- Heroku
- Git
- MERN Stack
- ReactJS

STRENGTHS

- App creation from planning to deployment
- Cross team communication and collaboration
- Branding and customer experience
- Data analytics and visualization with Tableau
- Market research and product development
- Strong written and verbal communication

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development | University of Washington **Professional & Continuing Education**

MAY 2020

Certificate of Completion

BA in Business Administration, Marketing Major | Seattle University **Albers School of Business and Economics**

JUNE 2015



PROJECTS

Quiz Panda

- Simple and responsive application that allows users to create surveys and guizzes and share them with friends via email to see who can get the highest score
- Primary role: Brainstorming the user experience and building out the front end with Handlebars, JavaScript, HTML, and Foundation CSS package
- Awards: Best App Overall, Best UI

MGR

- Marketing automation tool targeted to the music industry to help manage social media efforts for artists
- Primary role: Building out front end experience with React and Material-UI
- Node Packages: Nodemailer, Express, BCrypt, Uniqid dotenv, Cron
- Awards: Best UI

Google Books: Search & Save

• Responsive React application that uses the Google Books API to search for books and allows users to save or remove titles with MongoDB and Node.js back end

Weather Dashboard

• Application built with OpenWeather API that pulls current weather data and a five-day forecast for any city searched and displays the data in a clean, user-friendly dashboard. Searched cities are also saved to the users local storage for quick searches



EXPERIENCE

Marketing Strategy Consultant | Lenati LLC

JULY 2019-MARCH 2020

- Worked across key account such as Microsoft, T-Mobile, Vans, and others on various high-visibility marketing and program management projects
- Supported the Microsoft Office product marketing management team in preparation for the team's presence at Microsoft Ignite 2019 by leading session content creation between marketing and engineering teams, working with third parties to manage booth presence, and supporting major product announcements

Sr. Marketing Specialist | Xevo Inc.

MARCH 2016-JULY 2019

- Created key messaging for suite of new connected-car solutions as part of the company's new product launch to communicate value proposition across web, print, video, and presentations
- Assisted with six go-to-market solutions and integrated marketing plans in collaboration with key merchant and automaker brands
- Conducted consumer research to understand customer journey and improve roadmap in partnership with product engineering

Account Executive | Digital Intelligence Systems

JULY 2015-JANUARY 2016

- Managed accounts within the high-tech industry vertical, namely Microsoft and Facebook
- Proactively built trusting relationships with hiring managers at client sites by building an understanding of team needs and focusing on client success



VOLUNTEER

Social Media Strategist | HERE Seattle

JULY 2016-JANUARY 2019

 Non-profit dedicated to supporting an inclusive culture in technology and making a positive impact in the local community

Volunteer | Vera Project

SEPTEMBER 2012-PRESENT

• Non-profit community center focused on collaborative, youth-driven engagement in music and art



ACHIEVEMENTS

- Dean's List for Albers School of Business and Economics (Fall 2013-Spring 2015)
- Participated in Youth Executives of Color program at the University of Washington (2011-2012)
- Proficient in Spanish